Guide to the Judy Richardson Papers, 1963-2014 RL.10177
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- SNCC and Civil Rights Movement, 1963-1970; 1
  - Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (SNCC), 1963-1967; 1
    - A Guide for the Study of Negro History in the Churches (United Presbyterian Church), undated (Box 6)
    - Photograph of H. Rap Brown, undated (Box 6)
    - Quote From Chicago Song Lyrics, undated (Box 6)
    - "Hell No I Ain't Going" Bumper Sticker, yellow w/Stokley Charmichael, undated (Box 6)
    - "Hell No I Ain't Going" Bumper Sticker, red w/Stokley Charmichael, undated (Box 6)
    - "Black Power" Bumper Sticker, red, undated (Box 6)
    - Envelop from Mrs. Harry Belefonte and Ms. Diahann Carroll, undated (Box 6)
    - Note about Funds (fragment), undated (Box 6)
    - Possible Name Tag from the MFDP State Convention, "Worker, Judy Richardson, SNCC Greenwood", undated (Box 6)
    - Quote from Malcolm X, undated (Box 6)
    - Ramparts San Francisco and New York Staff listing, undated (Box 6)
    - Visitors Pass to US House Representatives, 1965 (Box 6)
    - All Black Freedom Now Party Card, undated (Box 6)
    - "Uncle" Booker T. Washington, undated (Box 6)
    - Newspaper Clipping from Tarrytown Daily News, 8/20/1964 (Box 6)
    - Black Panther Bumper Stickers, undated (Box 6)
    - Fisk Union Church Program, Fisk University, undated (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous Clippings (Folder 1 of 2), multiple dates (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous Clippings (Folder 2 of 2), multiple dates (Box 6)
    - Recommended Films for Use by SNCC at Institutes, undated (Box 6)
    - Handwritten Note About Instructional National Center, undated (Box 6)
    - Envelope Addressed to Judy Richardson From SNCC Atlanta, undated (Box 6)
    - Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party, RE: Letter to Challenge Supporters, 1965 (Box 6)
    - Unseat the Mississippi Congressional Delegation Signatures Form, undated (Box 6)
    - MFDP Handout - Congressional Record, January 4, 1965 (Box 6)
    - Handout - Clarion Ledger, 1965 (Box 6)
    - Envelope From the MFDP Wahsington Office, 1965 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence "The God's Truth" from Barry T. Dawson, 1965 (Box 6)
    - Letter from Barry T. Dawson w/photo clippings, RE: Protests in Philadelphia, PA, 1965 (Box 6)
    - Handwritten Letter from Mary King, undated (Box 6)
    - Letter from Dottie Zellner to Mary King, 1965-January-27 (Box 6)
    - Letter from a member of congress, Richard Ottinger, 1965-January-4 (Box 6)
    - Card from Dave (Christmas gift of Negro Digest subscription) + Envelope to JR attached, 1965-December-16 (Box 6)
    - Board of national missions of the united presbyterian church in the USA from Lois Montgomery (associate chairman) Women's division to JR, 1965-November-30 (Box 6)
    - Letter from Mr. M. Donatoni from JR, 1965-December-11 (Box 6)
    - Letter from JR to Mr. Charles Kinsloving, Jr. Bureau of advertising. 11 Feb. 1964. + attached: Letter from Charles M. Kinsloving, Jr. (22 Jan 1964), 1964 January-February (Box 6)
    - Letter from Ronald C. Sutton, Assistant in Admissions at Swarthmore College (15 Oct 1964), 1964-October-15 (Box 6)
    - Memo from Carol Stevens, Acting Secretary- Treasurer, 1964-December-21 (Box 6)
    - Sept 13 1965. Letter from Dave Lorenz, Negro Digest from Ivanhoe Donaldson, 1965-September-13 (Box 6)
    - July 19, 1965. Letter from James A. Dombrowski, Executive director to Jack Greensberg, Esq., Director of Naacp legal defense and education fund., 1965-July-19 (Box 6)
    - Letter from Julian Bond via the Julian Bond Campaign Office., undated (Box 6)
    - Letter to Atlanta Postmaster, 1965-February-23 (Box 6)
    - Letter from Martha (King?), 1965-November-10 (Box 6)
    - Letter to Lucy Montgomery., 1965-December-14 (Box 6)
    - Letter from Youth for Civil Rights c/o Jimmy Daniels, President Tarrytown, NY, undated (Box 6)
    - Letter from Dinky Romilly, 1964-November-23 (Box 6)
    - Letter from Carolyn Reese, 1965-October-22 (Box 6)
    - Western Union Mailgram to Mrs. Rap Brown. 2nd Page has list of Western Union Toll free numbers, undated (Box 6)
    - Correspondences with New York State Deputy Commissioner of Parole and Community Services, RE: H Rap Brown, 1976 July-August (Box 6)
    - "Women of the Movement" by Elizabeth Sutherland, letter enclosed, 1966-December-21 (Box 6)
    - "How long can the U.S government be hypocritical liars to Black people at home and abroad." Statement by CORE, undated (Box 6)
    - Notes for U.S Mission Trip, undated (Box 6)
    - Award, Poem bby Ramon "Ray" Durem, undated (Box 6)
    - Complaint Letter to Con Edison, RE: Payment Increase, undated (Box 6)
    - "For my people" by Margaret Walker, undated (Box 6)
    - "The Real Demands," The Afro-Americans Against the Vietnam War, undated (Box 6)
    - Oct. 1963. Case Study Conducted/published by SNCC, 1963-October-1 (Box 25)
    - 1964. Blue Note that says "History vindicates those who were right! James Forman (our man on the scene)" (Box 25)
    - 1964. Memorandum about financial situation of SNCC (Box 25)
    - The Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party Booklet. 1965, Nov. 5 (Issue 9)., 1965-November-4 (Box 25)
    - Map of Mississippi 1964 (Box 25)
    - Mississippi Summer Project Brochure, 1964 (Box 25)
    - 1964. Mississippi subversion of the right to vote (Box 25)
    - 1964. The Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party Booklet (Box 25)
    - Judy Richardson application for MS Summer Project Summer 1964 (folder 1of 2) (Box 25)
    - Judy Richardson application for MS Summer Project 1964 (folder 2 of 2) (Box 25)
    - Mississippi Summer Project Application 1964 (Blank) (1 of 2) (Box 25)
    - Mississippi Summer Project Application 1964 (blank) (2 of 2) (Box 25)
    - June 1964. Mississippi Summer Project orientation schedule, 1964-June-1 (Box 25)
    - Mississippi Summer Project. Staff Project Assignments, undated (Box 25)
    - Handwritten note on Hilton Garden inn memo paper, undated (Box 25)
    - COFO Memorandum, undated (Box 25)
    - Tentative administrative structure for Jackson Office. Undated. (Box 25)
    - Brief memorandum on federal civil rights authority, undated (Box 25)
    - Mississippi Handbook for Political Programs by COFO. Undated. (Box 25)
    - "A kind of memo" from Casey Hayden, Mary King, 1965 (Box 25)
    - 1964. SNCC News reprint: Allen's Army (Newsweek, feb. 24, 1965), 1965-February-24 (Box 25)
    - 1964. SNCC News reprint: Ole Miss Prof hits state voting barriers, 1964-April-18 (Box 25)
    - SNCC News reprint: The Nation, Incident in Hattiesburg by Howard Zinn, 1964-May-18 (Box 25)
    - SNCC press releases RE: MS Summer Project 1964 senate bill #1969 (Box 25)
    - SNCC Press releases RE: MS Summer Project 1964 MS legislate to outlaw summer civil rights project (Box 25)
    - 1964. Fact sheet on Leflore county, MS (Box 25)
    - SNCC Resource Sheet, undated (Box 25)
    - Some provisions for federal prosecution in Civil Rights from title 18 U.S Code, undated (Box 25)
    - 1964. Affidavit. Newspaper clipping from the Clarion Ledger attached with paperclip to affidavit (Box 25)
    - Handwritten notes RE: heart of atlanta motel demonstration affidavit coverage, 1964-January-11 (Box 25)
    - Notes on organizing by Charles McLaurin, undated (Box 25)
    - The Crusader Monthly Newsletter, 1964 May-June (Box 25)
    - Zambia Independence Celebration, Fisk African Students Union, 1964 (Box 25)
    - Correspondence RE: Affidavit permission for Random House publication of Missisippi, 1964-November-12 (Box 25)
    - Free Southern Theater Presents, undated (Box 25)
    - Letter to Robert Moses, single sided (October 22, 1964), 1964-October-22 (Box 25)
    - Letter from Judy Richardson to Random House, single sided. 1964, 1964-November-12 (Box 25)
    - Unsigned copy of letter to Random House from Judy Richardson. 1964., 1964-November-12 (Box 25)
    - Virginia Student Civil Rights Conference, Dec 4-6 1964 (Box 25)
    - SNCC Mass Mailings, 1964-September-17 (Box 25)
    - The Southern Patriot, Vol. 25, No. 1, undated (Box 25)
    - 1964. Dec 11 Letter (signed Jean and Judy), 1964-December-11 (Box 25)
    - Letter signed Judy Richardson and Stanley Wise, undated (Box 25)
    - Letter signed Stokely Carmichael, undated (Box 25)
    - Fifth district COFO Staff Meeting, 1965 April 14-17 (Box 25)
    - SNCC working paper of the vote Marion S. Berry, May 1965. "On programs…", 1965-May (Box 25)
    - Booklet: "reports by the staff of the Chicago SNCC Freedom Center May 1965", 1965-May (Box 25)
    - Freedom Now- Canadian Friends of SNCC Newsletter, 1965 July 6 (Box 25)
    - Congressional Record(89th Congress first session), Compliments of Hervey G. Machen, 1965 September 17 (Box 25)
    - WATS Reports, 1965-November-12 (Box 25)
    - SNCC Programs, 1965-February-23 (Box 25)
    - Freedom Primer Report, 1965 (Box 25)
    - Statement by Julian Bond, representative elect- Georgia House of representatives, 1966-January-10 (Box 25)
    - Program: Sunday evening with SNCC, 1966-March-20 (Box 25)
    - SNCC Town Hall program, 1966-April-2 (Box 25)
    - News from SNCC, 1966-May-16 (Box 25)
    - Press conference statement, 1966-May-23 (Box 25)
    - Press conference statement, 1966-May-21 (Box 25)
    - SNCC Research "coroner", 1966-May-26 (Box 25)
    - Bulletin: "What's happening in SNCC?" a special bulletin from the New York Office of SNCC, 1966-June-3 (Box 25)
    - 1966 June 23 Bulletin from New York Office of SNCC (Box 25)
    - 1966 Oct. Newsletter from the New York Office of SNCC, 1966-October-1 (Box 25)
    - Grass roots organizing project, 1966 December 1-8 (Box 25)
    - 1966 Nov Newsletter NY office of SNCC, 1966-November-1 (Box 25)
    - Report of the program secretary, 1966-December-2 (Box 25)
    - 1966 Nov 26 Report: Documents RE: National Anti-Draft Program for Blacks, 1966-November-26 (Box 25)
    - 1967 Jan Newsletter: Student Voice prospectus, 1967-January-1 (Box 25)
    - 1964 May 1, Notes on Puerto Rico for SNCC (Box 25)
    - SNCC statement to Afro-Asian missions to the United Nations, 1967-June-13 (Box 25)
    - 1967 Aug 20 Statement by Rap Brown in response to his imprisonment, 1967-August-20 (Box 25)
    - 1967 Nov 17 Statement of Mr. James Foreman, 1967-November-17 (Box 25)
    - 1967 Communique No. 1 Documents RE: House Arrest of H. Rap Brown SNCC Statement, 1967-December-22 (Box 25)
    - 1967 Citizens Amicus Brief Document Re. House Arrest of H. Rap Brown (Box 25)
    - SNCC Press Release, 1966-January-24 (Box 25)
    - SNCC Press Release, 1967-January-27 (Box 25)
    - SNCC Press Release, 1967-April-10 (Box 25)
    - 1967 Mar 7. Seven SNCC workers indicted, 1967-March-7 (Box 25)
    - MacLaurin vs. The State of Missisissipi, undated (Box 25)
    - Speech by Stokeley Carmichael at the University of Puerto Rico, 1967-January-25 (Box 25)
    - Eastman Kodak is out of focus, undated (Box 25)
    - Johnny Wilson statement, undated (Box 25)
    - Church bombings, Stokely Carmichael statement, 1967-March-15 (Box 25)
    - Aframerican "News for you" (SNCC) November 12, 1966, Vol II, 1966-1967 (Box 25)
    - Aframerican "News for you" (SNCC) January 12, 1967, Vol III (Box 25)
    - Where SNCC is, 1965 (Box 25)
    - SNCC Project Proposal and Grant Request, Fisk University. Undated. (Box 25)
    - Letter to J.R from Ivanhoe Donaldson. N.D, undated (Box 25)
    - SNCC Staff Letter. Undated. (Box 25)
    - Program outline for campus friends of SNCC groups. Undated. (Box 25)
    - Miscellaneous SNCC documents. Undated. (Box 25)
    - SNCC News of the field #10, 1966-April-29 (Box 25)
    - SNCC News of the field #11, 1966 April 27-May 8 (Box 25)
    - SNCC News of the field. Gould, Arkansas, undated (Box 25)
    - SNCC Campus Travellers Program Documents, 1964 (Box 25)
    - A little old report by Fay D. Bellamy. Undated. (Box 25)
    - History of Southern Student Organizing Committee (SSOC) Undated (Box 25)
    - Southern student organizing committee (Goals, By-laws, budget, history etc.), undated (Box 25)
    - Information on Southern College Campus Program (Campus Travellers)., undated (Box 25)
    - Central Committee Discussion of trips, undated (Box 25)
    - 1966 May 14-17 Report: Motions recommendations (sic), Mandates of SNCC, Central Committee (Box 25)
    - 1964 SNCC Campus Visit Request. Dr. Luther Foster Tuskegee Institute (Box 25)
    - 1964 SNCC Campus Visit Request. Mr. Robert Blockum, Knoxville College (Box 25)
    - 1964 SNCC Campus Visit Request. Dean Gomillion, Tuskegee Institute (Box 25)
    - SNCC Contracts and notes, campus travellers sticky notes of handwritten notes stuck together says: "7:30-Ealey turned self in", undated (Box 25)
    - SNCC Contracts and Notes, campus travellers 3 pages of sticky notes of handwritten notes says: "11:10 arrested office", undated (Box 25)
    - Small piece of note paper to Judy from R. Fellowsotne with Fellowstone's phone number, undated (Box 25)
    - 1 small piece of note paper signed Ruby, undated (Box 25)
    - "While you were out" Pink paper to Judy from Ivanhoe of Columbus, Ohio. Double sided, handwritten notes on back., undated (Box 25)
    - Directions from Holly Springs from Memphis (paperclipped) a)with notes about Don Charles b) note card about ernestine evans c)notecard about Henriette Schlanger (double sided)information about Henry Reeves on back., undated (Box 25)
    - List of Names, undated (Box 25)
  - Residential Freedom School, 1965; 2
    - SNCC, RE: Summary of Freedom School Curriculum, undated (Box 26)
    - Letter from Leonia-Vicksburg Committtee, 1965-May-11 (Box 26)
    - Letter from Episcopal Chirch of the Mission District, undated (Box 26)
    - Letter from Linda Schwarmann, 1965-March-11 (Box 26)
    - Letter from Pioneer Publishers, 1965-March-30 (Box 26)
    - Letter from Bay Area Office of SNCC, 1965-March-16 (Box 26)
    - Letter from Lucy, 1965-May-29 (Box 26)
    - Letter from James M. Estep, 1965-April-2 (Box 26)
    - Letter from Stein and Day Publishers, 1965-March-29 (Box 26)
    - Letter from Stern Family Fund, 1965-June-4 (Box 26)
    - Letter from Rev. Robert Stone, 1965-June-7 (Box 26)
    - Letter from Tom Hayden, undated (Box 26)
    - Letter to Highlander Center, 1965-June-10 (Box 26)
    - Letter from SNCC Chicago Office, 1965-June-14 (Box 26)
    - Letter from Stern Family Fund, 1965-June-15 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Rev. Gayraud S. Wilmore, 1965-June-17 (Box 26)
    - Letter from William Douthard, 2016-June-28 (Box 26)
    - Letter from Arthur G. Falls, 1965-June-29 (Box 26)
    - Letter from Cambridge Non-Violent Action Committee, 1965-June-30 (Box 26)
    - Letter from Silas Norman, 1965-July-1 (Box 26)
    - Letter from Films Incorperated, 1965-July-6 (Box 26)
    - Letter from United Presbytarian Church, 1965-July-7 (Box 26)
    - Letter from Tarrytowners for Civil Rights, 1965-July-9 (Box 26)
    - Letter from Staughton Lynd, 1965-July-9 (Box 26)
    - Letter from United Presbytarian Church, 1965-July-9 (Box 26)
    - Letter from United Presbytarian Church, 1965-September-1 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Tom Hayden, 1965-May-26 (Box 26)
    - Unidentified, RE: Poems inspired by Selma, undated (Box 26)
    - SNCC, RE: Freedom School Funds, undated (Box 26)
    - United Presbytarian Church, RE: Cordele, GA Freedom School Logistics, 1965-June-24 (Box 26)
    - Letter to John Churchville, RE: Philadelphia Students to Freedom School, 1965-June-24 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Michael Standard, RE: Freedom School Update, 1965-September-10 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Sylvia Fischer, RE: Freedom School Information, 1965-May-26 (Box 26)
    - Letter to John Churchville, RE: Philadelphia Students Recruitment, 1965-May-25 (Box 26)
    - Letter to David Barry, RE: New York Students to Freedom School, 1965-May-27 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Stern Family Fund, RE: Freedom School Funding, 1965-May-27 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Michael Standard, RE: Freedom School Funding, 1965-May-27 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Myles Horton, RE: Freedom School Funding, 1965-May-27 (Box 26)
    - Letter to John O'Neal, RE: Freedom School Attendance, 1965-June-9 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Gayraud Wilmore, RE: Freedom School Location, 1965-June-11 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Medical Committee for Human Rights, RE: Medical Exams, 1965-June-24 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Leni Zeiger, RE: Reply to Information on Freedom School, 1965-June-15 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Robert Barrie, RE: Request for Freedom School Hosting, 1965-May-8 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Rev. L.S. Brown, RE: Request for Support for Cordele School, 1965-May-6 (Box 26)
    - Description of Conditions in Cordele, Georgia, 1965-March-7 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Monroe Sharp, RE: Chicago Freedom School Proposal, 1965-April-6 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Jimmy Garrett, RE: Chicago Freedom School Proposal, 1965-April-6 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Rennie Davis, RE: Chicago Freedom School Proposal, 1965-April-5 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Tom Hayden, RE: Chicago Freedom School Proposal, 1965-April-5 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Essau Jenkins, RE: Chicago Freedom School Proposal, 1965-April-5 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Dr. Staughton Lynd, 1965-March-17 (Box 26)
    - Letter from Staughton Lynd, 1965-March-25 (Box 26)
    - Unknown addressee, 1965-October-10 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Gil Moses, 1965-June-24 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Major Horn, Brooklyn CORE, 1965-June-24 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Dr. Staughton Lynd, 1965-June-23 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Mike Standard, ACRAF, 1965-September-30 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Mr. and Mrs. Noel Day, 1965-May-26 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Danny Beagle and John McFerren, 1965-May-26 (Box 26)
    - Letter from Carl Djerassi, 1965-June-30 (Box 26)
    - Letter to John Urbaine, 1965-July-15 (Box 26)
    - Letter from SNCC Office, 1965-July-2 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Carl Djerassi, 1965-July-15 (Box 26)
    - Letter to William Douthard, 1965-June-28 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Bob Epstein, 1965-July-3 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Thomas Moffett, 1965-July-2 (Box 26)
    - Letter from Thomas Moffett, 1965-June-29 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Films Incorperated, 1965-July-2 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Miss Howe, Brandon Films, 1965-July-2 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Mrs. Schutter, Contemporary Films, Inc, 1965-June-28 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Lawrence Guyot, 1965-June-29 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Carl Djerassi, 1965-June-28 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Frank Willis, 1965-June-28 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Stokely Carmichael, 1965-June-26 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Byron Bushing, 1965-June-26 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Dr. Arthur Falls, 1965-June-26 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Roger Doyle, 1965-June-25 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Walt Sheppard, Philadelphia Tutorial Project, 1965-June-25 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Bryant George, Board of National Missions, 1965-June-25 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Bob Stone, United Presbyterian Church, 1965-October-28 (Box 26)
    - Letter from Michael Standard, 1965-October-5 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Robert Gottlieb, 1965-June-4 (Box 26)
    - Letter to Lucy Montgomery, 1965-May-26 (Box 26)
    - Summary of Freedom School Curriculum, undated (Box 26)
    - Outline for Residential Freedom School Program, undated (Box 26)
    - SNCC Executive Committee Memo, RE: Residential Freedom School Proposal, undated (Box 26)
    - Prospectus for Residential Freedom School (2 copies), undated (Box 26)
    - Residential Freedom School Report, by Judy Richardson, undated (Box 26)
    - Miscellaneous Notes and Drafts, re: RFS; Handwritten by Judy Richardson, undated (Box 26)
    - List of Contact Information, 1965-June-7 (Box 26)
    - Staff Report/Evaluation of Residential Freedom School (fragment), undated (Box 26)
    - Report on Three Incidents at the Residential Freedom School, undated (Box 26)
    - Films for RFS, undated (Box 26)
    - Signed Permission Slips for Residential Freedom School Participants, 1965 (Box 26)
    - Financial Records, re: Residential Freedom School, undated (Box 26)
    - About the Freedom School: Special to the Adults and Yound People of Cordele, undated (Box 26)
    - Prospectus for Residential Freedom School (2 versions), undated (Box 26)
    - The Residential Freedom School (information), undated (Box 26)
    - Outline for Residential Freedom School Program (3 copies), undated (Box 26)
    - Guidelines for Discussion, RE: Use of Gillespie-Seldon Institute for a Residential Freedom School..., undated (Box 26)
    - List of Participants, Residential Freedom School, 1965 (Box 26)
    - An Evaluation of Residential Freedom School by Profit Barlow, undated (Box 26)
    - Report from Student in Residential Freedom School, by Rubye Nell Brooks, undated (Box 26)
    - SNCC Staff Memo, RE: Residential Freedom School (2 copies), undated (Box 26)
    - Residential Freedom School Report, 1965 August (Box 26)
    - SNCC Freedom School in Chicago, Woodie C. Lewis, 1965-September-14 (Box 26)
  - Death of Ralph Featherstone, 1970; 3
    - Demands to Federal Government re: Featherstone's and Che's death, Black United Front of Detroit, 1970-March-11 (Box 7)
    - In memoriam: William "Che" Payne and Ralph "Feather" Featherstone, Concerned Black Women, 1970 (Box 7)
    - Pride orientation bulletin No. 1, 1970-March-11 (Box 7)
    - Confidential letter to accompany "Official statement on the political assassination of Ralph Featherstone and William Che Payne", undated (Box 7)
    - Pamphelet re: Featherstone's life, undated (Box 7)
    - Official statement on the political assassination of Ralph Featherstone and William Che Payne, 1970-March-11 (Box 7)
    - Account of the deaths of Ralph Featherstone and William Payne, undated (Box 7)
    - Information of memorial for Ralph Featherstone, undated (Box 7)
    - Black statement of concern and solidarity (Ralph Featherstone), 1970-March-13 (Box 7)
    - Statement re: Ralph Featherstone, undated (Box 7)
    - Note to Sister Frances Beal, Brothers Dan Aldrich, James Boggs, Bob Lucas, and William Strickland, undated (Box 7)
    - On the death of Brother Featherstone and Brother Che, Pan African Students Organization in the Americas, Inc, 1970-March-14 (Box 7)
    - Ralph Featherstone press clippings, undated (Box 7)
- United Church of Christ Commission for Racial Justice, 1982-1993; 2
  This series includes published Civil Rights Journal commentaries, clippings, and columns written by Richardson as the Commission's Director of Information. Also includes some press information and other materials relating to various UCC projects in the mid-1980s.
  - Press coverage of UCC CRJ, 1986-1987 (Box 7)
  - Commentaries, 1984-1987 (Box 7)
  - Staff/Administration, 1984-1990 (Box 7)
  - NYC Taxi Commissio hearings re: racist cab drivers, 1980s (Box 7)
  - Correspondence + clippings Re: Ben Chavis, 1988-1991 (Box 7)
  - Programs/events, 1991 (Box 7)
  - Clippings, undated (Box 7)
  - Civil Rights Journal correspondence, clippings, 1982-1989 (Box 7)
  - Ben Chavis coverage, 1993 (Box 7)
  - UCC Civil Rights Journal, 1983 (Box 7)
  - UCC Civil Rights Journal, 1984 (Box 7)
  - UCC Civil Rights Journal, 1985 January-February (Box 7)
  - UCC Civil Rights Journal, 1985 March-April (Box 7)
  - UCC Civil Rights Journal, 1985 May-June (Box 7)
  - UCC Civil Rights Journal, 1985 July-August (Box 7)
  - UCC Civil Rights Journal, 1985 September-October (Box 7)
  - UCC Civil Rights Journal, 1985 November-December (Box 7)
  - UCC Civil Rights Journal, 1986 January-March (Box 7)
  - UCC Civil Rights Journal, 1986 April-June (Box 7)
  - UCC Civil Rights Journal, 1986 June-September (Box 7)
  - UCC Civil Rights Journal, 1986 October-December (Box 7)
  - UCC Civil Rights Journal, 1987 (Box 7)
  - Criminal Justice Issues, 1983 (Box 24)
  - Newsletters: Commission News and Synod Spectrum, 1984-1986 (Box 24)
  - NYC racism/Committee Against Racially Motivated Police Violence, 1983-1987 (Box 24)
  - Freedom Riders 1986/1987 (Box 24)
  - Welfare Hotel camp, 1987 (Box 24)
  - South Africa divestment, 1986 (Box 24)